$(function() {

    var $lists = [
        {
          "category": "History",
          "id": "622a1c3c7cc59eab6f9517be",
          "correctAnswer": "The Bayeux Tapestry",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "The Hastings Tapestry",
            "The Calais Tapestry",
            "The Wynton Tapestry",
          ],
          "question": "Which famous tapestry commemorates the Norman conquest of England?",
          "tags": [
            "medieval",
            "middle_ages",
            "uk",
            "wars",
            "history",
            "art"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "medium"
        },
        {
          "category": "Society & Culture",
          "id": "622a1c357cc59eab6f94fd02",
          "correctAnswer": "Spinoza",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Thomas Hobbes",
            "Denis Diderot",
            "Albert Camus"
          ],
          "question": "Which philosopher famously said 'I can control my passions and emotions if I can understand their nature'?",
          "tags": [
            "philosophy",
            "quotes",
            "society_and_culture"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "hard"
        },
        {
          "category": "Film & TV",
          "id": "6256987c9da29df7b05f728a",
          "correctAnswer": "Sebastian Stan",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Stellan SkarsgÃ¥rd",
            "John Slattery",
            "Jeff Goldblum"
          ],
          "question": "Which actor plays the role of Bucky Barnes in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
          "tags": [
            "mcu",
            "film",
            "acting",
            "marvel",
            "comics",
            "film_and_tv"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "medium"
        },
        {
          "category": "Film & TV",
          "id": "622a1c347cc59eab6f94fa79",
          "correctAnswer": "Kevin Kline",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Alec Guinness",
            "Martin Landau",
            "River Phoenix"
          ],
          "question": "Who won the 1988 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Otto in A Fish Called Wanda?",
          "tags": [
            "academy_awards",
            "acting",
            "film",
            "film_and_tv"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "hard"
        },
        {
          "category": "Film & TV",
          "id": "622a1c347cc59eab6f94f8dc",
          "correctAnswer": "Peter Sellers",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "James Cagney",
            "Michael Douglas",
            "Johnny Depp"
          ],
          "question": "Which actor played the role of Chance the Gardener in Being There?",
          "tags": [
            "acting",
            "film",
            "film_and_tv"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "hard"
        },
        {
          "category": "Science",
          "id": "622a1c377cc59eab6f95051a",
          "correctAnswer": "study of horses",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "cetaceans - whales, dolphins, and porpoise",
            "the field of dermatological anatomical pathology",
            "the medical study of the causation of disease"
          ],
          "question": "What is Hippology the study of?",
          "tags": [
            "science"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "hard"
        },
        {
          "category": "Film & TV",
          "id": "622a1c377cc59eab6f9506e3",
          "correctAnswer": "Gerard Butler",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Hugh Jackman",
            "Robert Redford",
            "Jim Carrey"
          ],
          "question": "Which actor has featured in films including 300 and James Bond: Tomorrow Never Dies?",
          "tags": [
            "film",
            "acting",
            "film_and_tv"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "medium"
        },
        {
          "category": "Geography",
          "id": "623b580bfd6c701a92118394",
          "correctAnswer": "USA",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Croatia",
            "Spain",
            "Australia"
          ],
          "question": "In which country would you find the Carlsbad Caverns National Park?",
          "tags": [
            "tourist_attractions",
            "geography"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "hard"
        },
        {
          "category": "Arts & Literature",
          "id": "622a1c347cc59eab6f94f953",
          "correctAnswer": "Winnie the Pooh",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "In Our Time",
            "Nine Stories",
            "1984"
          ],
          "question": "Which book contains the character 'Eeyore'?",
          "tags": [
            "literature",
            "fictitious_characters",
            "arts_and_literature"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "easy"
        },
        {
          "category": "Music",
          "id": "62506471e12f6dec240bdfb3",
          "correctAnswer": "House of Pain",
          "incorrectAnswers": [
            "Haddaway",
            "Digable Planets",
            "Brownsville Station"
          ],
          "question": "Who had a hit in 1992 with Jump Around?",
          "tags": [
            "songs",
            "one_hit_wonders",
            "1990's",
            "music"
          ],
          "type": "Multiple Choice",
          "difficulty": "medium"
        }
      ];
    var $questionList = $lists;
    $lists.forEach((item, i, array) => {
      $questionList[i].question = item.question;
      let answers_string = item.incorrectAnswers;
      answers_string.toString().split(",")
      let answers = answers_string
      answers.push(item.correctAnswer);
      $questionList[i].answers = answers;
      $questionList[i].correctAnswer = item.correctAnswer;
      $questionList[i].index = i;
    });
    let result = 0;
      

    var $category = $("#category");
    var $difficulty = $("#difficulty");
    var $country = $("#country");
    var $box = $("#box");
    var $questions;
    var $questionTemplate = $("#question-template").html();

    function question_view (questionArray) {
      let html_template = `
      <div id="${questionArray.index}">
        <div class="field">
          <div class="control">
          <h3>Result: <strong id="result"> ${result} </strong>, Num: ${Number(questionArray.index) + 1} / ${$questionList.length}</h3>
            <p>${questionArray.question}</p>
          </div>
        </div>
        <div class="column is-4 options">
      `
      var options = questionArray.answers;
      let optIndex = 0;
      for (option in options) {
        html_template += `

          <input type="radio" name="answer" value"${options[optIndex]}" id="${options[optIndex]}">
          <label for="${options[optIndex]}">${options[optIndex]}</label>
          <br>
        `
        optIndex++;
      }
      html_template += `</div>
      <button class="button next" ques-i="${questionArray.index}" id="salt"> next > </button>`
      html_template += `</div>`

      document.getElementById("question-template").innerHTML = html_template;
      // $questionTemplate.append(html_template);
    }

    // $("#take-test").on("click", () => {
    //     var letTest = {
    //         category: $category.val(),
    //         difficulty: $difficulty.val(),
    //         country: $country.val()
    //     };
    //     // $("#test-query").css("display", "none");
    //     $("#test-query").remove()
    //     $.ajax({
    //         type: "GET",
    //         url: `https://the-trivia-api.com/api/questions?limit=20&categories=${letTest.category}&difficulty=${letTest.difficulty}&region=${letTest.country}`,
    //         success:  (questions) => {
    //             // $questions = questions;
    //             $.each(questions, (i, question) => {
    //               $questions[i].question = question.question;
    //               $questions[i].answers = question.incorrectAnswers;
    //               $questions[i].answers.append(question.correctAnswer);
    //               $questions[i].correctAnswer = question.correctAnswer;
    //               $questions[i].index = i;
    //             })
    //             question_view($questions[1], 0);
    //         },
    //         error: () => {
    //             alert("error getting questions!!");
    //         },
    //     });


        
    // });


    $("#take-test").on("click", () => {
      // var letTest = {
      //     category: $category.val(),
      //     difficulty: $difficulty.val(),
      //     country: $country.val()
      // };
      $("#test-query").css("display", "none")
      // $.ajax({
      //     type: "GET",
      //     url: `https://the-trivia-api.com/api/questions?limit=20&categories=${letTest.category}&difficulty=${letTest.difficulty}&region=${letTest.country}`,
      //     success:  (questions) => {
      //         // $questions = questions;
      //         $.each(questions, (i, question) => {
      //           $questions[i].question = question.question;
      //           $questions[i].answers = question.incorrectAnswers;
      //           $questions[i].answers.append(question.correctAnswer);
      //           $questions[i].correctAnswer = question.correctAnswer;
      //         })
      //         question_view($questions[0], 0);
      //     },
      //     error: () => {
      //         alert("error getting questions!!");
      //     },
      // });
      question_view($questionList[0]);


    });

    $box.delegate(".next", "click", () => {
      // mark = $("#pick").val()
      // mark = document.getElementById('answer').value;
      // let mark = document.querySelector("input[type='radio'][name=answer]:checked").value;
      let mark = $("input[name=answer]:checked", ".options").prop("id");
      let done = 0;
      // var ele = document.getElementsByName('answer');
              
      // for(let i = 0; i < ele.length; i++) { 
      //   if (ele[i].checked) { 
      //     mark = ele[i].attr("name");
      //   }
      // }

      if (!mark) {
        return alert("pick an answer");
      }
      index = $(".next").attr("ques-i");
      index = Number(index);
      if ((mark == $questionList[index].correctAnswer) && (done == 0)) {
        result += 5;
        $("#result").html(`${result}`);
      }

      index += 1;
      if (index < $questionList.length) {
        document.getElementById("question-template").innerHTML = "";
        // $questionTemplate.remove();
        question_view($questionList[index]);
      } else {
        alert(`${result}`);
        done += 1;
      }



    })
});